petsmart.ca 2019-06-26

# Privacy Policy | PetSmart

PetSmart wants you to know how we collect, use, share and protect information about you online and in our stores. By interacting with us, you consent to our use of information that is collected or submitted as we describe in our privacy policy. We may change or add to this privacy policy, so we urge you to review it periodically.

### WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED

Types of personal information we collect include:

  * Your name 
  * Your mailing address 
  * Your e-mail address 
  * Your phone (or mobile) number 
  * Your credit/debit card number 
  * Your purchase/return/exchange information 
  * Your wish list information 
  * Your date of birth or age 
  * Your location 
  * Your pet’s information (name, breed, date of birth, gender, veterinary information, photographs, etc.) 

If you choose not to provide personal information, we may not be able to provide you with requested products, services or information.

Automated Information Collection

We may connect information collected automatically with information we already have about you in order to identify you as a PetSmart customer. If we are able to identify you as a PetSmart customer, we may, for example, link your activity on our website to your activity in our stores. This allows us to provide you with a personalized experience regardless of how you interact with us – online, in-store, mobile, etc.

PetSmart Automated Information Collection

We and our service providers use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us through your computer or mobile device. This information, which includes the pages you visit on our site, which web address you came from, the type of device you are using, purchase information and checkout process, search terms and geographic location, helps us recognize you, customize your website experience and make our marketing messages more relevant. These technologies also enable us to provide features such as storage of items in your cart between visits and SMS/text messages you have chosen to receive. We also use Flash cookies for fraud prevention and other purposes.

In order to provide the best customer experience possible, we also use these technologies for reporting and analysis purposes, including how you are shopping our website, the performance of our marketing efforts, and your response to those marketing efforts.

Third-Party Automated Information Collection

In certain instances, we allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our website and to use that information to serve ads for PetSmart products and services or for the products and services of other companies when you visit our website or other websites. These companies use non-personally identifiable information during your visits to this and other websites in order to customize your shopping experience and to provide advertisements about products and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These parties typically use a cookie or a third party web beacons, and similar technologies to collect this information. Some browsers have a 'do not track' feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. Neither PetSmart nor its third party providers have a systematic method for ensuring that browser 'Do Not Track' requests are consistently honored. However, you may learn more about online advertising and opt out of the use of your web browsing activity to serve targeted ads by companies that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance by visiting <http://youradchoices.ca/choices/>.

Our Mobile Website

Our mobile website collects the same type of information outlined throughout this policy.

Our Mobile Programs

By participating in any of our mobile programs you are agreeing to receive automated marketing phone calls and text marketing messages at the phone number you provide at opt-in. Your consent to receive such marketing messages is not required to make a purchase. You understand and agree that the phone calls made and text messages sent to your mobile phone/device may be generated using automated telephone dialing technology. You agree to notify PetSmart at 1-855-537-0295 in the event that you change or disconnect your mobile phone number.

Message and data rates may apply. All charges are billed by and payable to your mobile service provider. PetSmart will not be liable for any delays in the receipt of any messages as delivery is subject to effective transmission from your mobile service provider.

PetSmart text alerts are recurring. For help, you can text 'HELP' to 25252. To cancel, you can text 'STOP' to 25252. If you text to cancel, you will receive one additional message confirming that your cancelation request has been received. Alternatively, you can call 1-855-537-0295 to cancel your participation in a mobile program. Once you cancel, you are welcome to opt back into the program at any time.

PetSmart reserves the right to remove subscribers at our discretion. Terms are subject to change.

PetPerks® Loyalty Program – Automatic Number Assignment

Beginning in 2014, PetSmart may automatically assign a PetPerks number to customers for whom we have other identifying information, such as a phone number or email address. This enables our customers to take advantage of our many promotions throughout the store and will allow us to customize our offers to better serve you.

User Experience Information

In order to improve your online shopping experience, to help with fraud identification, and to assist our customer service representatives in resolving issues you may experience in completing online purchases, we use tools to monitor certain user experience information. This includes: Login information, IP address, data regarding pages visited and ads clicked, specific actions taken on pages visited (e.g. information entered during checkout process), and browser information.

Social Media Widgets

petsmart.ca includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, Google Plus, YouTube and Twitter widgets. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

Information from Other Sources

We may collect data that’s publicly available. For example, information you submit in a public forum (e.g. a blog, chat room, or social media) can be read, collected, or used by us and others, and could be used to personalize your experience. You are responsible for the information you choose to submit in these instances.

We also obtain information provided by third parties. For instance, we obtain information from companies that can enhance our existing customer information to improve the accuracy and add to the information we have about our customers (for example, adding address information). This improves our ability to contact you and increases the relevance of our marketing by providing better product recommendations or special offers that may interest you.

In-Store Cameras

We use in-store cameras for security purposes and for operational purposes such as measuring and observing customer traffic patterns.

Geo-Location Tracking

Certain mobile devices contain geo-location tracking capability. We may use such capability or other geo-location tracking technology to generally identify your location in our store or your close proximity to it for marketing, to generate coupons and other offers, for analytical purposes and to prompt our associates as to which customers may need help.

### HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION USED

Examples of how we use the information we collect include (but are not limited to):

Product and Service Fulfillment

  * Fulfill and manage purchases, orders, payments, returns/exchanges, or requests for information about our products and services in our stores, website, or mobile website, or to otherwise serve you. 
  * Connect with PetSmart regarding customer service via our customer service center, or on social media platforms. 
  * Provide services such as Favorites. 
  * Administer contests. 
  * Notify you of any products you have purchased that are subject to recall or withdrawal. 

Our Marketing Purposes

  * Deliver promotional offers, coupons, mobile coupons, in-store receipt messages, e-mails, mobile messages, and social media notifications. 
  * Provide interactive features of the website or mobile applications, such as product reviews or marketing communications and other information regarding products, services and promotions. 
  * Administer promotions, surveys, and focus groups. 
  * Automatically assign a PetPerks® loyalty card number to you. 
  * Use a review you submit for commercial purposes to promote the products or services in your review. We may also include the user name and city/province you gave when submitting your review. 

Internal Operations

  * Improve the effectiveness of our website, stores, associates, mobile experience, and marketing efforts. 
  * Conduct research and analysis. 
  * Perform other business activities as needed, or as described elsewhere in this privacy policy. 

Photographs and Information About Your Pet

We may take photographs of your pet and send them to you or your designated family members/agents via email or text to let you know, for example, that your pet is ready for pick up (e.g. in the PetSmart Grooming salon), that your pet is doing well (e.g. during a stay at PetsHotel) or to commemorate that s/he has learned a new trick (e.g. in training class). We may also use the photographs on social media. Unless you ask the store associate who took your information not to do so, your email and phone number will automatically be entered into our customer database and may be used for operational and marketing purposes as provided for in this policy. Your pet’s photograph(s) may also be uploaded into the database and associated with your name.

Fraud Prevention

To prevent fraudulent transactions, monitor against theft and otherwise protect our customers and our business

Legal Compliance

Investigate claims, incidents or inquiries regarding customers, associates, vendors and pets, assist law enforcement, animal control, health officials and/other government entities to respond to legal, regulatory, health and similar inquiries

### HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED

PetSmart

We share the information we collect within PetSmart, Inc., which includes all of PetSmart’s subsidiaries and affiliates, including PetSmart Home Office, Inc., PetSmart Puerto Rico, LLC and PETM Canada Corporation. We also share information with companies that are closely associated with PetSmart, such as Banfield Pet Hospital (Medical Management International, Inc.), PetSmart Charities, Inc., and PetSmart Charities Canada. These entities may use this information to offer you products, services and charitable opportunities that may be of interest to you.

Service Providers

We may share the information we collect with companies that provide support services to us (such as printers, e-mail marketers, mobile marketing, analytics providers, web hosting providers, call center service providers, payment processors, coupon delivery vendors, or data enhancement providers) or that help us market our products and services. These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions.

Legal Requirements

We may disclose information we collect when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply applicable terms and conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our company, our customers, pets in our care or others.

Elsewhere at Your Direction

At your direction or request, we may share your information. For example, if you create a wish list and elect to make it available to the public, your information will be accessible on our website, mobile or social applications, or in our stores.

Sharing with Other Companies (for their marketing purposes)

We may communicate to you information or special offers from other companies or organizations. In such cases, we do not provide your personal information to them and they will not know your identity unless you choose to transact with them, in which case their privacy policies will govern your relationship. With your consent, we may share your personal information with other companies, or organizations that are not part of PetSmart. These companies and organizations may use the information we share to provide special offers and opportunities to you.

Sharing Aggregate Information with Third Parties

We may share aggregate non-personally identifiable information (information that does not directly identify an individual) with third parties for any lawful purpose.

Business Transfers

If some or all of our business assets are sold or transferred, we may transfer the corresponding information regarding our customers. We also may retain a copy of that customer information.

### WHAT CHOICES DO YOU HAVE

Opt-Out and Access Choices

You may 'opt-out' of certain marketing communications. Most of our marketing communications are sent by email and direct mail, though you may also opt out of telephone calls, texting and online behavioral advertising as well. You may also access or change your personal information or ask us to do so.

To do so yourself, you may:

  * Follow opt-out 'unsubscribe' instructions in promotional e-mails we send to you. 
  * Log on to petsmart.ca to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us. 
  * Log on to your PetPerks loyalty account to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have a PetPerks account with us. 
  * Set the _Help_ function of your browser to not receive cookies. PLEASE NOTE: this may make it difficult or impossible to make a purchase on petsmart.ca. 
  * Delete our mobile app from your smart phone and follow the phone manufacturers’ directions on how to delete cookies or other technology received from our mobile website. For many phones, you will go to the Settings function to do this. 
  * Text STOP to text messages (SMS/MMS) we send to you. 

If you need our help, please:

  * Call our PetPerks line at 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) and tell them which information you would like to access or which types of promotional materials you want to opt-out of. Please note you may need to speak with a manager. 
  * Call our customer service number at 1-888-839-9638 (U.S. Customers) 1-321-309-9065 (Customers Outside of the U.S.) and tell them which information you would like to access or which types of promotional materials you want to opt-out of. Please note you may need to speak with a manager. 
  * **E-mail:** [CustomerCare@petsmart.com](mailto:CustomerCare@petsmart.com) and tell them which information you would like to access or which types of promotional materials you would like to opt-out of. 
  * **Mail:** PetSmart, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
19601 North 27th Avenue  
Phoenix, AZ 85027 
  * When mailing or emailing us, please include your full name, address, phone number, e-mail address and your PetPerks account number if you know it. Also, tell us what information you would like to access, change or add to our 'opt-out' list. This will help us process your request. 

If you 'opt-out' of our PetSmart marketing communications, you may continue to receive business communications such as order confirmations, product recall information, appointment confirmations or other administrative information. Your information will likely remain in our database, we will just mark it as inactive so that you do not receive marketing materials from us.

More Details on How to Opt-Out

Direct Mail

If you do not wish to receive special offers, coupons and other promotional mail directly from us, you may opt out by logging onto your PetPerks loyalty account and opting out of receiving mail or by calling 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) as described above. Note - This opt-out does not apply to any promotional materials that may come inside the packaging of your online purchases.

Telephone

If you do not wish to receive promotional telephone calls, you may opt out by logging onto your PetPerks loyalty account and opting out of being contacted by phone or by calling 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) as described above. This opt-out does not apply to operational phone calls, for example, confirmation of delivery address or pet services appointments.

E-mail

If you do not wish to receive promotional e-mails from us, you may opt-out by logging onto your PetPerks loyalty account and opting out of contact by e-mail or by calling 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) as described above. You also have the ability to opt out of promotional e-mails via the unsubscribe link included in each promotional e-mail.

Mobile – Texts, Mobile Apps and Mobile Website

We may distribute coupons, offers and other information via text messages or mobile applications to customers who have requested this information or who have downloaded a PetSmart application.

To opt out of a specific mobile messaging campaign, reply **'STOP'** to text messages we send you.

Our mobile applications may take you to our mobile website, which acts similarly to our petsmart.ca website. To opt-out, delete our mobile app from your smart phone and follow the phone manufacturers’ directions on how to delete cookies or other technology received from our mobile website. For many phones, you will go to the Settings function to do this.

Online - petsmart.ca Cookies

The _Help_ function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time. If you set your computer not to receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services may not be provided to you, and accordingly, you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the petsmart.ca features (for instance, you will be able to browse the site, but may not be able to make a purchase).

Online - Third Party Cookies

Certain companies provide services that analyze information regarding visits to petsmart.ca. They use technology such as cookies and web beacons to collect this information. The _Help_ function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time. If you set your computer to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services may not be provided to you.

PetPerks® Loyalty Program – Automatic Number Assignment

If you no longer want to have a PetPerks number, you may opt out by logging onto your PetPerks loyalty account and cancelling your account or by calling 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) as described above.

Neither PetSmart nor its third party providers have a systematic method for ensuring that 'Do Not Track' functionality in certain browsers can operate to prevent such tracking. You may be able to opt-out of certain types of 'tracking' by utilizing the opt-out service at the Network Advertising Initiative at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed>.

### HOW DO YOU ACCESS AND UPDATE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

In order to keep your personal information accurate and complete, you may access or update some of it in the following ways:

If you have created a petsmart.ca or petperks.com account, you may log in and update your account information, including contact, and billing information. You may also call 1-866-PET-PERKS (1-866-738-7375) and ask for the information you are trying to access or change. Please note: You may need to ask for a manager.

### HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION PROTECTED

Security Methods

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect your personal information. When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit or debit card number, we use industry-standard methods to protect that information. However, no e-commerce solution, website, database or system is completely secure or 'hacker-proof.' You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse.

E-mail Security

'Phishing' is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking you for your personal information, do not respond. We will never request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal information through e-mail.

Children’s Personal Information

We recognize the particular importance of protecting privacy where children are involved. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13.

Questions or Concerns

If you have general questions or concerns about how we use your personal information, please contact us through:

  * **E-mail:** [CustomerCare@petsmart.com](mailto:CustomerCare@petsmart.com)
  * **Mail:** PetSmart, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
19601 N. 27th Avenue  
Phoenix, AZ 85027 
  * **Phone:** Toll-free: 1-321-309-9065 You may need to ask for a manager. 

PETSMART PRIVACY POLICY SCOPE

This privacy policy applies to all current or former customer personal information, except for information collected by or provided in connection with completing an application for employment with PetSmart. Our website may offer links to other sites. If you visit one of these sites, you may want to review the privacy policy on that site. In addition, you may have visited our website through a link or a banner advertisement on another site. In such cases, the site you linked from may collect information from people who click on the banner or link. You may want to refer to the privacy policies on those sites to see how they collect and use this information.

UPDATES TO THIS POLICY

If we intend to use or disclose your personal information in any way materially different than what we say in this privacy policy or make any other material changes, we will make reasonable efforts to revise this policy. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the 'Revised' date below.

Revised April 2016
